- Hi, it's me Tim Dodd, the Everyday Astronaut.
- 嗨 这是我的蒂姆·多德 每天的宇航员
Have you ever accidentally used a tablespoon instead of a teaspoon?
你曾经不小心使用的汤匙代替茶匙？
Or maybe you grabbed a metric wrench when you were trying to loosen up a 9/16" bolt?
或者 也许你抓住了 当你试图放松9/16" 螺栓扳手指标？
Or maybe you've heard someone say that something weighs a ton and you have to ask them,
或者 也许你听说过有人说的东西重达一吨 你要问他们
now is that a imperial ton or a metric ton?
现在是一个帝国吨或一吨？
Luckily, when most of us mix up units,
幸运的是 当我们大多数人混淆了单位
it likely just leads to our food tasting bad,
它可能只是导致我们的食物味道不好
or maybe strips a bolt,
也许条螺栓
or just simply leads to a really annoying argument
或者只是导致非常恼人的说法
between which is the right measurement system.
在它们之间是合适的测量系统
But when NASA and Lockheed Martin mixed up the units for the Mars Climate Orbiter,
但是 当美国航空航天局和洛克希德·马丁公司混合了单位为火星气候轨道
it led to the loss of a $327 million mission to Mars.
它导致了$ 327万登陆火星的损失
Welcome to another episode of biggest facepalms or spaceflight history, otherwise known as spacepalms.
欢迎到最大facepalms或航天史上的另一个情节 也称为spacepalms
This is where we're going to take a look at a mission
这就是我们要看一看任务
or an event that almost certainly lead to everyone in Michigan troll collectively facepalming.
或者一个事件 几乎肯定会导致大家在密歇根州巨魔集体facepalming
Now this one in particular is a very well known story.
现在这一个 特别是一个非常著名的故事
One you may have heard your physics professor regale you
一个你可能已经听说过您的物理学教授盛宴你
with when talking about the importance of units.
与谈论单位的重要性时
But honestly, I don't think I've actually heard the correct story all the way through
不过说实话 我不认为我实际上已经听到了正确的故事 一路过关斩将
and I definitely didn't know what truly happened before I made this video.
我绝对不知道我之前做这个视频是什么真正发生的事情
So today, let's take a look at what was suppose to happen,
所以 今天 让我们来看看什么是假设发生
what wound up happening and why.
什么清盘发生以及为什么
After all, this is a classic lesson that will be passed down for generations and generations.
毕竟 这是将代代相传两代经典的一课
And it's a fun story to tell.
而且这是一个有趣的故事
So, let's get started.
所以 让我们开始吧
The year 1999, back when websites look like this.
1999年度 回来时 网站的这个样子
"The Matrix" was released and the Cher song "Believe" was the number one hit.
“黑客帝国”的出台和雪儿歌曲“相信”是头号打击
NASA was hoping to have a big hit on their hands as well
NASA希望能在他们的手一个很大的打击 以及
with an exciting new Mars Orbiter that would study the Martian climate,
一个令人兴奋的新的火星轨道 将研究火星的气候
known as you guessed it, the Mars Climate Orbiter.
被誉为你猜对了 火星气候轨道
NASA set new guidelines for some less expensive and smaller probes for interplanetary missions
美国航空航天局制定新准则对一些更便宜和更小的探针星际飞行任务
after a panel on small spacecraft technology was formed in 1994.
上小型航天技术面板后形成于1994年
These new probes would be under 1000 kilograms with more focused scientific instruments
这些新的探测器将在1000公斤 蓄有更集中的科学仪器
instead of Swiss Army knife do it all style spacecraft from years prior.
而不是瑞士军刀做往年所有样式飞船
The first mission in this new program was called the "Mars Global Surveyor" which launched in 1996,
在这项新计划的第一个任务被称为其在1996年推出的“火星全球探勘者号”
on top of a Delta II from SLC-17A Cape Canaveral Space Force Station,
从SLC-17A卡纳维拉尔角航天部队站德尔塔II之上
or Cape Canaveral Air Force Station, as it was known at the time.
或卡纳维拉尔角空军基地 因为它是当时已知
This first probe would map the surface of Mars with more detail than ever before,
这第一个探测器将在火星表面有更详细的比以往任何时候都映射
which would help pave the way for future Mars landers.
这将有助于铺平道路 为未来的火星登陆器的方式
The Mars Climate Orbiter was to follow the success of the Mars Global Surveyor
火星气候轨道是跟随火星全球探勘者号的成功
and would be taking with it some of the instruments
并会用它采取了一些手段
that were originally designed for the Mars Global Surveyor.
最初被设计为火星全球探勘者号
The two would be a mini powerhouse for studying Mars from orbit.
二是从轨道研究火星一个小型发电站
The spacecraft found up being 2.1 meters wide.
飞船发现了是宽2.1米
1.6 meters tall and two meters deep.
身高1.6米及深两米
It would weigh only 638 kilograms
这将仅重638千克
making it capable of being launched on a Delta II with only four solid rocket boosters,
使得它能够在德尔塔II被推出只有四个固体火箭助推器
but despite its small way,
但尽管它的小路上
it was still stuffed to the gills with scientific instruments including the Mars Orbiter Camera,
它仍然塞满了科学仪器 包括火星轨道器照相机鳃
the Mars Orbiter Laser Altimeter, the Thermal Emission Spectrometer,
在火星轨道激光测高仪 热发射光谱仪
a Magnetometer and electron reflectometer,
一个磁强计和电子反射
the ultra-stable oscillator and a Mars Relay signal receiver.
超稳定振荡器和火星中继信号接收器
Saying those out loud feels like I was making half of them up,
话说那些大声感觉就像我正在其中的一半了
I probably should have tried to sneak in the specs on the end line for the rotary girder
我也许应该尝试在端线的规格潜行的旋转梁
to see if any you guys are actually paying attention.
看看是否有你们实际上关注
The vehicle had eight monoprop thrusters
车辆有八个monoprop推进器
each with 22 Newtons of thrust photo trajectory corrections
每个推力相片轨迹校正的22牛顿
and four smaller 0. 9 Newton thrusters for attitude control.
和四个较小的0.9牛顿推进器姿态控制
Lastly, it had one larger main engine a leros 1B
最后 它有一个较大的主引擎莱罗斯1B
that provided 640 Newtons of thrust for the Mars insertion burning.
所提供的推力为640牛顿的火星插入燃烧
Mars Climate Orbiter had a unique design.
火星气候轨道器有一个独特的设计
It only had a single large solar panel off to one side,
它只有一个单一的大太阳能电池板偏向一侧
which was capable of 500 watts at Mars,
这是能够以火星500瓦
which side note because Mars is 50% further away from the Sun than the Earth is,
这侧面说明因为火星是50％ 从太阳更远高于地球
due to the inverse square law, a solar panel on Mars is about 45% as powerful as it is on Earth.
由于平方反比定律 在火星的太阳能电池板是约45％那样强大 因为它是在地球上
On December 11th 1998, at 1845 UTC,
在1998年12月11日 在1845 UTC
the Mars Climate Orbiter took off from Cape Canaveral Air Force Station SLC-17A
火星气候轨道从卡纳维拉尔角空军基地SLC-17A起飞
beginning its 10 month journey to Mars.
开始其10个月的旅程火星
One of my favorite things about this launch is
我最喜欢的事情有关此次发布的是
the Star-48B spin stabilized solid propellant third stage.
星-48B自旋稳定的固体推进剂第三阶段
That's right, its spin stabilize So if there's any minor offset in the thrust,
这是正确的 其自旋稳定所以如果有任何轻微的推力抵消
you can know it out by spinning the stage.
您可以通过旋转台知道了
Once the burn is complete,
一旦刻录完毕
there's a YoYo Despin mechanism that mostly knows how the spin,
有这么多是知道如何旋溜溜球Despin机制
it stuff like this that I think is just so cool.
它这样的东西 我认为是如此的酷
So the little probe was on its way, everything looking good.
于是小探头在它的途中 一切都看起来很不错
And like all deep space missions,
像所有的深空飞行任务
it's normal to do a few correction burns along the way to make sure you nail your target.
这是正常不过的事情 一路上几个修正烧伤 以确保你钉你的目标
And that's no big deal I mean, this is done all the time.
而这没什么大不了我是说 这样做是所有的时间
There were four course corrections performed on December 21st 1998,
有于1998年12月21日进行了四个课程更正
March 4th, July 25th and September 15th 1999.
3月4日 7月25日和1999年9月15日
There was another optional course correction planned just one day prior to the Mars insertion burn,
有计划之前 火星插入燃烧仅仅一天另一个可选的方向修正
but it was denied by management
但被拒绝管理
because they thought based on prior trajectories that the probe was on course.
根据以前的轨迹 因为他们认为探针是在课程
Alongside the course corrections,
除了课程更正
the spacecraft also perform something called angular momentum desaturations or AMDs.
飞船还进行一些所谓的角动量去饱和或AMD的
Many spacecraft do this but especially the Mars Climate Orbiter,
许多航天器做到这一点 但特别是火星气候轨道器
because it had that single sided solar panel.
因为它有这样的单面太阳能电池板
It experienced more solar pressure on one half of the spacecraft than the other.
它经历了飞船上比其他的二分之一以上的太阳能压力
By the way, fun side note,
顺便说一句 有趣的边注
solar pressure is the momentum of the massless photons exerting pressure on a spacecraft
太阳能压力是无质量的光子上的航天器施加压力的动量
and it's not solar wind.
这不是太阳风
Solar wind is composed of particles with mass ejected by the sun like nucleons and electrons.
太阳风是由颗粒的质量与喷出由太阳等核子和电子
Thanks to Scott Manley and the rest of space Twitter for helping clarify that for me.
由于斯科特·曼利和空间的Twitter的帮助澄清我的休息
Okay, so your spacecraft is ever so slightly rotating in a direction you don't want.
好了 你的飞船的方向非常轻微转动你不想要的
And in order to keep the reaction wheels inside the spacecraft
而为了保持飞船内部的反应轮
that helped maintain orientation from having to work overtime,
这有助于不必加班保持方向
you can perform an AMD to reset the spacecraft back to its ideal orientation
您可以执行AMD重置飞船返回其理想的方向
and keep those reaction wheels happy and not overworked.
并保持这些反应车轮开心与不开心过度劳累
Now each and every single time the spacecraft performs any desaturation maneuver
现在每个和每一次飞船执行任何饱和演习
or any correction burn,
或任何修正烧伤
or really any maneuver the exact impulse or the exact amount
还是真的任何操纵精确冲动或确切数额
of time each and every thruster is fired, is recorded,
时间每个推进器点火 记录
and then that's sent back down to earth
然后这送回脚踏实地
so Mission Control can calculate exactly how much the spacecraft change its trajectory.
所以任务控制可以计算出飞船究竟有多大改变它的轨迹
Even if it's by the teentiest, tiniest amount during these corrections.
即使这些补偿时是由teentiest 最小的量
But now mind you mission control can still track the probe
但是 现在你心里任务控制中心仍然可以跟踪探头
and its trajectory in deep space on the way to Mars.
其在道路上的火星是深空轨道
But the primary way of doing so is using Doppler shift
但是 这样做的主要方法是利用多普勒频移
and that's not incredibly accurate at some portions of the journey,
这不是在旅程的某些部分令人难以置信的准确
especially when the changes in velocity are perpendicular to the vantage point.
特别是当在速度变化是垂直于所述的有利位置
Think of it like this Doppler can very precisely tell if something is speeding up or slowing down,
想想看这样的多普勒可以非常精确地知道如果事情是加快或减慢
moving straight, away or towards you.
直移动 远离或朝向你
But it can't really tell if something is speeding up side to side from Earth's vantage point,
但它真的不能告诉如果事情是从地球的制高点加快一边到另一边
which for a good portion of the journey to Mars, is exactly what's happening.
这对于火星之旅相当一部分 究竟是发生了什么
So generally guidance teams will precisely calculate the vehicle's exact trajectory
所以 一般的指导小组将精确地计算出车辆的准确轨迹
after the Hohman transfer burn that sends the probe on its way to Mars.
在Hohman转让后刻录发送探测的道路上火星
And so long as any outside force doesn't act upon the vehicle, which spoiler it's space.
而只要任何外力不会在车辆上 其搅局它的太空行动
The variables are well accounted for and well known.
这些变量以及占和众所周知的
The vehicle will end up exactly where it's calculated to a surprising degree of accuracy.
车辆最终会正是它的计算准确性的令人吃惊的程度
But this also means that they need to account for each and every thruster fire
但是 这也意味着他们需要考虑每一个推进器火
as even those tiny little impulses change the exact destination of the vehicle.
因为即使是那些小小的冲动改变车辆的确切的目的地
Even if only a tiny amount, if you do something enough,
即使只有一个很小的量 如果你做的东西就够了
it ends up adding up over time to a very drastic change.
它最终将随着时间的推移 以一个非常剧烈的变化
Now, of course when you're aiming at a planet that's over 200 million kilometers away from you,
现在 当然 当你瞄准一个行星 它是200多万公里 距你
a tiny error could either mean missing that planet,
一个微小的错误可能意味着要么缺少的星球
or perhaps even worse, smacking right into it.
或许更糟的是 打孩子走进去
And NASA was aiming to only miss Mars by 200 kilometers or so.
和NASA进行了200公里左右 旨在只错过火星
So there was very little room for error.
所以有非常小的闪失
And in general,
而在一般情况下
you want to aim and get as close as you can safely get to the planet that you're trying to be captured by.
要瞄准并获得尽可能接近你可以放心地去说你要来捕捉这个星球
Now, of course, if you're on a planet that has an atmosphere,
现在 当然 如果你对有大气的行星
you need to take that into consideration and not get too low.
你需要考虑到这一点 并没有得到太低
But the closer you are, the less energy it takes to get captured into orbit.
但是你越近 它需要的能量越少得到捕获到轨道
On September 15th 1999 just one week prior to the Mars encounter and insertion burn,
9月15日1999年火星相遇并插入刻录之前只有一个星期
NASA performed the fourth and final trajectory correction maneuver,
NASA进行的第四次也是最后弹道修正机动
which placed its trajectory 226 kilometers above the surface of Mars.
其中放置火星的表面上方226公里其轨迹
Perfect for the Mars orbital insertion.
完美的火星轨道插入
But following that burn,
但随之而来的是烧伤
the navigation team noticed their calculations and their observations didn't match.
导航团队注意到他们的计算 他们的观察结果不匹配
And in fact,
而事实上
the observed trajectory kept getting lower and lower to the point
被观测的轨迹不停地越来越低的点
where they saw it go all the way down to just 150 kilometers,
在那里他们看到它一路下降到只有150公里
but that was still safely above the minimum altitude of 80 kilometers.
但当时仍安全地80公里 最低海拔以上
Now if you go below 80 kilometers
现在 如果你去下面80公里
Mars's atmosphere will still bite up your fragile little spacecraft and rip it to shreds.
火星的大气层仍然会咬你的脆弱的小飞船和它撕得粉碎
Just imagine that tiny little fragile solar panel getting knocked about by the Martian winds.
试想一下 小小的脆弱的太阳能电池板越来越撞倒有关火星风
Oh, humanity.
哦 人性化
Just 24 hours before the orbital insertion burn
轨道插入烧伤只是前24小时
as the gravitational effects of Mars grew stronger
火星的引力效应越来越强
the newly observed trajectory was putting the spacecraft at only 110 kilometers.
新观测的轨迹是把航天器在只有110公里
But again, that's still above the 80 kilometers that's survivable.
但同样 这仍然高于80公里这就是生存
So they proceeded despite some vocal opposition of some of the operators.
因此 他们继续尽管一些运营商的一些口诛笔伐
At 9 o'clock and 46 seconds UTC on September 23 1999,
上午9时46秒UTC 9月23日1999年
the insertion burn began.
插入刻录开始
Everything was performing as planned at first.
一切都进行的最初计划
Miss control expected a loss of signal when the spacecraft went behind Mars,
小姐控制预期的信号丢失时 飞船去火星的背后
and they had an exact time they expected that to happen.
他们有他们希望这样的事情发生的确切时间
The first signs of serious trouble cropped up
严重麻烦的第一个迹象出现了
when the loss of signal occurred 49 seconds earlier than expected,
当信号的损失发生较早49秒于预期
and it was even further drilled in by the fact
并且它在的事实进一步钻探
that signal was not required 21 minutes later as they expected,
该信号是不需要21分钟后来因为他们预期
despite trying for two full days.
尽管尝试了整整两天
- I'm sorry to report that we have a serious problem with the Mars Climate Orbiter.
- 我很遗憾地告诉你 我们与火星气候轨道器的一个严重问题
We may in fact be facing a loss of mission.
我们可能会在事实上面临任务的损失
- So what actually happened?
- 那么到底发生了什么？
Was there something wrong with the insertion burn?
是有什么错插入烧伤？
Was it that NASA was reading the oxygen kilometers when the probe was saying miles.
是不是 美国宇航局正在读氧气公里时 探针说英里
Find out after we hear a word from this week's sponsor, banana for scale.
了解之后 我们听到从本周的赞助商规模一句话 香蕉
- Are you tired of measuring stuff based on some old guy's feet?
- 你是否厌倦了基于几个老家伙的脚测量的东西？
(screaming)
（尖叫）
Are you constantly asking Siri how many ounces are in a pint, only to get the wrong answer?
你是否经常问Siri的多少盎司是一品脱 只得到错误的答案？
- Hey Siri, how many ounces are in a pint?
- 嘿Siri的 有多少盎司是一品脱？
- [Siri] Austin is the capital of Massachusetts?
-  [Siri的]奥斯汀是美国马萨诸塞州的首府？
- Is it just too easy knowing there's a 1000 milliliters in a litre?
- 它太容易知道有一个千毫升在一升？
Or perhaps you're measuring horses in hands and you just (mumbles)
或者 也许你正在测量手的马 你只（喃喃自语）
Introducing banana for scale the one true unit of measure.
介绍香蕉的规模措施的一个真正的单元
- Okay, so the answer each and every time the spacecraft perform those desaturation maneuvers,
- 好了 所以每次每一个答案 飞船执行这些饱和演习
it would report back what it did to correct for the angular momentum.
它会汇报它的所作所为来校正角动量
Now the internal guidance and control was performing perfectly fine.
现在内部的指导和控制进行了完美的罚款
Maintaining control and keeping proper orientation of the spacecraft no problem.
保持控制并保持飞船的正确方向没有问题
The problem is what the space craft was sending back down to earth was Newton seconds.
问题是什么飞船被发回脚踏实地是牛顿秒
And the software in the ground station was reading those results as pound seconds.
而在地面站软件是读那些结果磅秒
And reporting those results to the guidance and navigation teams off by a factor of 4.4 or five times.
和报告这些成果的指导和导航小组关闭的4.4五倍的一个因素
So in other words, each time the spacecraft did a desaturation maneuver,
因此 换句话说 每次飞船做了一个饱和动作
it reported back to the ground what exactly it did.
它报告给地面它到底做了什么
The data with the wrong unit,
用错误的单元中的数据
then was put into the model for the spacecraft's trajectory by the guidance team.
然后放入模型由指导团队飞船的轨迹
Now since the units were wrong,
现在 因为该单位是错误的
the calculated trajectory was also wrong.
计算出的轨迹也是错误的
Now the funny thing is because these angular momentum desaturation burns were so low energy
现在 有趣的是 因为这些角动量饱和度烧伤是如此低能量
being off by 4.45 times was hardly noticeable.
4.45倍被关闭是难以察觉
So throughout the journey,
所以整个旅程
every one of those little tiny events was doing a tiny little bit,
那些一点微小的事件 每一个在做一个小点点
but the estimated trajectory thought they were doing about 4.45 times more work.
但估计的轨迹以为他们在做约4.45倍的工作量
This was compounded by the fact that because the Mars Climate Orbiter had just a single solar panel,
这是由事实 因为火星气候探测者号有只是一个单一的太阳能电池板复合
it had to perform over 10 times more desaturation events than its sister spacecraft,
它有超过10倍的去饱和事件比它的姊妹宇宙飞船执行
the Mars Global Surveyor, which had two solar panels.
在火星全球探勘者号 其中有两块太阳能板
So how could this have been prevented?
因此 这怎么可能是可以避免的？
Well, like most things, it'd be easy to put blame on one person or group
好了 最喜欢的东西 它会很容易把责任推到一个人或一群人
but in reality, it's kind of a whole swath of small problems
但在现实中 它是一种小毛病全幅的
and putting the blame on anyone doesn't really solve the problem.
而诿过于人并没有真正解决问题
The first and most obvious problem and solution is to make sure all units are the same.
第一个也是最明显的问题和解决方案是确保所有单位都是一样的
Lockheed Martin took a lot of flack for delivering units in pounds seconds,
洛克希德·马丁公司花了很多宣传的为英镑提供秒单位
as it was intended to be delivered in Newton's seconds.
因为它的目的牛顿秒的时间内交付
But oddly, the blame game continues.
但奇怪的是 指责的游戏仍在继续
When it was discovered the code given to Lockheed Martin was in pound seconds in the first place,
当人们发现给洛克希德·马丁公司的代码是英镑秒位居第一
and they didn't catch it.
他们没抓住
Specifically a set of code called Small forces,
具体来说称为小势力的代码集
which was wrong from day one.
这是从天一个错误
Well, and then again, that no one caught the air and quality control at NASA either.
好了 然后再次 没有人抓到在美国航空航天局空气质量控制两种
And then you can keep going and saying it was a management problem,
然后你就可以继续下去 并说这是一个管理问题
considering several things factors were overlooked starting with the initial design of the spacecraft.
考虑几件事情的因素被忽视先从飞船的初步设计
Most notably that no one from guidance and navigation was on the design team,
最值得注意的是 从制导和导航没有人设计团队
which led to a less than desirable and hard to navigate spacecraft in the first place.
这导致在第一位置比所希望较少 很难导航航天器
But then ignoring the requests of the guidance navigation team
但随后忽略了导航服务团队的要求
to perform the desaturation maneuvers 180 degrees apart from each other
以彼此进行去饱和动作180度分开
would have negated the problem before it arose.
它发生之前会否定这个问题
By doing asymmetrical burns for the desaturation also led to imparting additional unwanted velocity.
通过这样做不对称烧伤的饱和度也导致施加额外的不必要的速度
And lastly,
最后
the teams were seeing erroneous data that didn't line up with our calculated trajectories,
球队正在看到的是不符合我们的计​​算轨迹排队错误的数据
but it was ignored.
但它被忽略了
This was amplified and actually quite obvious
这被放大 实际上是相当明显
that something was wrong in the last week of the mission as the spacecraft got closer to Mars.
事情不妙 在上周的使命 作为航天器走近火星
A few members of the team spoke up verbally
团队的一些成员发话了口头
and wanted to do a t-minus 24 hour correction burn to raise the approach.
并希望做一个T型减24小时校正刻录到提高的方法
But they were denied because the concerns weren't filed correctly.
但他们拒绝 因为担心没有被正确地提出
And due to some mis organization of authority.
而且由于一些错误的权威组织
Those that spoke up were seen as out of line.
那些说话了被看作是脱节的
So really like all things,
所以很喜欢所有的东西
this wasn't a black and white topic.
这不是黑与白的话题
It's fairly nuanced and has a lot of tiny little things that added up to one big thing.
这是相当细致入微 具有很多的加起来一件大事小小的东西
And at the end of the day,
并在这一天结束时
the thing happened and the best thing we can do is learn from it
的事情发生了 我们能做的最好的事情是从中吸取教训
and prevent it from ever happening again.
并阻止其再次发生
In fact, the problems discovered with the Mars Climate Orbiter
事实上 这些问题与火星气候轨道器发现
was cross checked with the Mars Polar Lander,
与火星极地着陆器交叉检查
which was also on its way to Mars at the exact same time.
这也是的道路上火星在精确的同一时间
And although it didn't have the same problem,
虽然它没有同样的问题
it ended up not touching down softly for completely different reason.
它结束了不是完全不同的原因 触地轻声
- Volcom Mars op.
-  VOLCOM火星运算
- CFOM, go ahead.
-  CFOM 勇往直前
- Yeah, Sam, I'm sorry to report that all we have is HKTM at this point.
- 是啊 山姆 我很遗憾地通知我们只有HKTM在这一点上
It seemed to have been a nominal no contact MR Pass
这似乎是一个名义上没有接触MR通行证
- Copy that Mark thanks for, thank for hanging in there with us.
- 复制 马克感谢 感谢挂在那里与我们联系
- But the lesson learned has been passed down to every new generation of navigators and engineers.
- 但是吸取了教训 一直流传到每一代新导航和工程师
It's a valuable lesson and hopefully a lesson everyone
这是一个宝贵的经验 并希望一节课大家
who designed spacecraft for the first humans going to Mars has listened to closely.
谁第一个人类去火星的航天器设计听了密切
So to summarize,
因此 要总结
a spacecraft on its way to Mars
的道路上火星的航天器
needed to fight off the solar pressure exerted onto the single sided solar panel
击退施加在单面太阳能板将太阳能压力所需
by doing some angular momentum desaturations with its small attitude thrusters.
通过做一些角动量去饱和与它的小的态度推进
Each time the vehicle did a desaturation maneuver,
每次车辆做了一个饱和动作
it recorded what it did and reported it back down to earth
它记录了它的所作所为 并报告其回落到地球
where the recorded thruster firings were misinterpreted by software
这里记录的推进器点火是由软件曲解
as pounds seconds of force instead of Newton seconds,
作为力 而不是牛顿秒磅秒
leading to very tiny deviations in the calculated trajectory.
导致计算出的轨迹非常微小的偏差
These tiny deviations were so small,
这些微小的偏差如此之小
they went mostly unnoticed until the spacecraft encountered Mars at 57 kilometers in altitude,
他们大多去了被忽略 直至飞船在海拔遇到火星在57公里
instead of the calculated 226 kilometers,
而不是计算226公里
which likely made the spacecraft burn up in the Martian atmosphere,
这可能来自飞船烧了对火星大气层
leading to the loss of the mission.
导致任务的丢失
So let's not be so hard on ourselves when we make little errors.
因此 让我们不能对自己这么辛苦 当我们做小的错误
Or maybe be nicer to each other
或者 也许是更好彼此
understanding each and every single one of us is capable of mistakes.
了解每一个和我们每一个人能够失误
It's simply part of being human.
它只是人类本性的一部分
So what do you think?
Did you learn something?
Do you think it's just a simple unit error?
Or do you think there's a lot more to it than that?
Let me know your thoughts and why metric is the better unit of measurement in the comments below.
Now I promise I'll do a few more of these space POM videos to try
and fill the gap between some of my long form videos.
Because trust me, those are getting a bit ridiculous even for me.
I owe a huge thank you to my Patreon supporters for helping make content like this possible.
I have the best community of people that help me research and script these videos.
And fact check before this all comes public.
So they let me know if I've done anything wrong.
And it's actually a really fun place to hang out.
So if you wanna gain access to our exclusive subreddit,
our exclusive discord channel and exclusive live streams
and just hang out with really awesome space enthusiasts go to patreon.com/everydayastronaut.
And while you're online,
be sure to check out my awesome webstore for shirts like this pointy end up flaming down,
or the lunar mission shirt or the brand new future Martian society shirt.
There's just lots of cool stuff.
So check back often these are all limited run
and they might not be there the next time you check back.
That's everydayastronaut.com/shop.
Thanks everybody.
That's gonna do it for me I'm Tim Dodd,
the everyday astronaut.
Bringing space down to earth for everyday people.
(upbeat music)